Xavier Athletic Advisory Board meeting minutes and related documents
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections
Xavier Athletic Advisory Board meeting minutes and related documents
1895-1996
1935-1996
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections Phone: 513-745-4821 http://www.xavier.edu/cm/archives
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Athletic Advisory Board
1.25 linear feet (3 boxes)
Meeting minutes, correspondence and other documents of the Xavier University Athletic Advisory Board.
XUA-16
History of Xavier University Athletic Advisory Board
The Board has been known by various names in the course of its history. Its earliest title seems to have been The Athletic Council. It existed under that name as early as 1923. In 1935, as a result of Xavier's loss of North Central Association accreditation over the football program, the Athletic Council was abolished and replaced by the Board of Athletic Control, also referred to as the Athletic Advisory Council. By the 1970's it was simply called the Athletic Board. More recently it has been called the Athletic Advisory Board.
Not specified
Scope and Content
Meeting minutes, correspondence and related documents of the Xavier Athletic Advisory Board.
Not specified
Statement of Arrangement
Materials are arranged in this general manner:
Meeting agenda, minutes and related documents arranged chronologically
Board correspondence arranged chronologically
Documents relating to the men's basketball coach search of 1979
Restrictions on Access
Restricted access.Please contact the Xavier University Archives staff.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Organizations/Corporations:
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio)--Sports
Detailed Description of The Collection
- Minutes and Related Papers, 1935-1948 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Minutes and Related Papers, 1958-1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Minutes and Related Papers, 1969-1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Minutes and Related Papers, 1975-1996 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Executive Committee Minutes, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Constitutions, 1953-1992, undated (Box 1, Folder 5a)
- Correspondence and Historical Programs, 1894-1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1957-1964 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1964-1968 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, 1974-1979 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, 1979-1996 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Basketball Coach Search, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Basketball Coach Search Candidates, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 18)